Christopher Leja

Brooklyn, NY, 11221 | 970-219-4766 | christopher.leja@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn | Medium | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks. My writing background has given me extensive experience with learning syntax, creative problem solving, and linguistic pattern recognition, skills that translate directly to writing code. I've edited a best-selling poetry collection and am a multiple Pushcart Prize nominee. Coding offers exciting new opportunities for connection through dynamic, interactive stories, and I'm excited to help tell them.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROFICIENT IN: JavaScript, React, React Native, Redux, Ruby, Rails, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, PostgreSQL, MySQL WORKING KNOWLEDGE: TypeScript, Node.js, Python, Django, MongoDB

PROJECTS

MAIESTRO – A music app designed to jumpstart creativity

Frontend | Backend | Video Demo | Live Demo

Maiestro renders a dynamic, customizable keyboard, allowing users to play, record, and save songs. Users can choose from over 100 distinct instrument sounds. If stuck, users can connect to a neural network through Magenta.js to hear different approaches to continuing their melody. Built with React, Rails, Magenta.js, and the react-piano library.

DRUMBLR - A virtual drum machine

Frontend | Backend | Video Demo

Drumblr is designed as an homage to late 80's/early 90's step-sequencers. Offers dynamic beats, customizable tempos, and custom presets to allow users to create, play, and edit beats in real time. Users can save their own beats as presets, use a built-in equalizer to customize the sound, and load previous beats. Built using React, Rails, and the midi-sounds library.

SUPER PET BROS. UNLEASHED - A Pokémon style browser game

GitHub | Video Demo

Super Pet Bros. Unleashed is a battle game that allows users to create, customize, save, and duel with their selected champions. Champions can be customized with personality, move sets, and stats. Battle mechanics and pages dynamically update in response to user input and move effects. Built using vanilla JavaScript, Rails, HTML5 and CSS3.

EXPERIENCE

SANS SERIF Writer, IMPACT Conference 2019-20 San Francisco, CA 04/2019 - Present

- Wrote and reviewed materials for <u>Charles Schwab's IMPACT Conference</u> to ensure quality and clarity.
- Created guide materials clarifying workshops and speaker biographies for thousands of conference attendees.

CLEAN FUELS DEVELOPMENT COALITION

Bethesda, MD

02/2019 - 02/2020

02/2012 - 02/2020

- Communications Consultant
- Collaboratively developed long-term media strategies and handled media outreach for a national ad campaign.
- Oversaw social media campaigns that generated over 50,000 new engagements.
- Collaborated on campaigns resulting in core messages appearing in *Forbes, The Hill* and the *Des Moines Register*.

SELF-EMPLOYED

Traveling

Teaching Artist/Freelance editor

Orchestrated and executed multiple national and international tours as a teaching artist.

- Designed, organized and conducted hundreds of readings and workshops.
- Served as primary creative editor for Clementine von Radics' <u>Mouthful of Forevers</u>, among others.
- Facilitated writing workshops in universities, high schools, and juvenile detention facilities.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL

Brooklyn, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

02/2020 - 06/2020

Lewis & Clark College

Portland, OR

05/2012

Bachelor of Arts, English Major, Communications Minor